Muhammad Fathir Irhas

Jakarta - Tangerang

□ (+62) 812-2444-1284 | 🗷 fathir.irhas@outlook.com | 🏕 mfathirirhas.github.io | 🖫 mfathirirhas | 🛅 mfathirirhas

Summary_

Highly passionate and enthusiast Software Engineer mostly in backend development and little frontend stuffs. Always learning to improve skills and willing to share. Able to work independently and in team. Write good and testable code and refactor them if needed. Provide solutions and improvement if needed. Have experiences developing system and services.

Education

Telkom University Bandung, Indonesia

SARJANA KOMPUTER(S.KOM)

2012 - 2016

GPA: 3.34

Experience _____

Tokopedia Jakarta, Indonesia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jun 2018 - Now

- · Working in Fintech Team
- · Contribute in Saldo Tokopedia, Tokocash(before shutdown), Internal Tools, and some investment products
- Develop system and services that do CRUD in either Postgre, MySQL, and/or Redis(cache)
- · Develop system and services that do communicate each other synchronously/asynchronously using REST, gRPC, GQL, cron, or NSQ
- Develop some frontend of the product(Saldo Tokopedia and internal tools)
- Add, Fix, Change, and Maintain services and features in Fintech products
- · Provide solutions and improvement to products features and services
- Monitor services running(server log, datadog, prometheus/grafana)
- · Execute tickets coming from users through ops team relating to issues in products
- · Participate in daily and sprint
- · Participate in team sharing session
- · Collaborate with other team to provide interface and integration to/from Fintech's products/services and provide solutions

Anabatic Technologies

Serpong Tangerang, Indonesia

TECHNICAL CONSULTANT

· Monitor client's app running

• Support product development and customization

Emporia Digital Raya, Anabatic Technologies

Serpong Tangerang, Indonesia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER(JUNIOR)

Nov 2016 - Dec 2017

Jan 2018 - Jun 2018

- · Work in Agile running sprint every 2 weeks.
- · Maintain Main site.
- Develop UI components using HTML, CSS, Javascript, and JSP.
- · Develop web services in form of REST APIs, firebase push notif, mail services, authentication for mobile apps using PHP, Java and MySQL.
- · Versioning and deployment.

Chevron Pacific Indonesia Duri Riau, Indonesia

INTERNSHIP

2015

- Internship under UTC-POD Team in IT Departement.
- Create simple web app using C# ASP.Net to handle request for well surveys.

Skill

GOLANG, JS, POSTGRE, MYSQL, REDIS, NSQ, API, REST, GRPC, GQL, TEST

Others:

C#, Python, Java, PHP(Laravel & Codeigniter), Wordpress, Excel

Activity_

Informatics Lab, Telkom University

Bandung, Indonesia

Held and support main practicum

PRACTICUM ASSISTANT 2013 - 2015

Software Engineering Lab, Telkom University

Bandung, Indonesia

2015 - 2016

LAB ASSISTANT

• Study and research group. Held and support some lab activities including tutoring, mentoring, sharing knowledge, workshop, movies, game, game development community indie game developer enthusiast and other activities.

Hackathon MDK 2.0 Bandung, Indonesia

CONTESTANT Oct 2015

- Participate in second Hackathon held by Telkom around Indonesia.
- Developed simple web services to be consumed by Android

Other_

Blog: https://mfathirirhas.github.io/blog **More**: https://mfathirirhas.github.io/resume **Portfolio**: https://mfathirirhas.github.io/portfolio